# Stephane Couvreur

Data Scientist

# SUMMARY

A young team playing data scientist. I have a passion for machine learning and big data, real-time processing and distributed systems. My experience has been in computer vision for medical images, and graph analytics for anti-money laundering.

### EXPERIENCE

October 2018 - Present

# Data Scientist Feedzai, Lisbon

- Developed tree-based machine learning models detecting transaction fraud with 57% recall at 1% FPR. The models performed at peak throughputs of 2000 events per second with sub-200ms latency at five nines.
- Implemented data processing pipelines in Apache Spark and Hadoop to train models on up to 1B rows of historical data, and inject the data into production databases (DynamoDB & Cassandra) prior to deploy.

June 2017 - September 2018

# Research Assistant

Great Ormond Street Hospital, London

- Embedded in a team of engineers and clinicians working on applications of data science in paediatric cardiology.
- Developed data mining and unsupervised machine learning tools in Python and R to extract useful clinical patterns in cardiac magnetic resonance imaging (CMRI).
- · Accelerated medical image segmentation workflow using convolutional neural networks trained on labelled images in Tensorflow. Whole-heart computer vision workflow achieved an AUC of 0.752.
- Two successful grant applications from NVIDIA and Medtronic totalling £2500.

## Projects

HACKATHONS Alibaba Cloud Tianchi, London – Jan 2018

Kaggle Days, Dubai - April 2019

Posters UCL Launch Campaign - 2016

# TECHNOLOGIES

Intermediate Knowledge Matlab, C/C++, Awk, Sed,

L⁴TEX, Git, Theano, PyTorch

Advanced Knowledge Python 3, R, Bash, PostgreSQL,

Tensorflow, Keras.

Apache Hadoop, MapReduce, Spark

Estr. da Luz, 1600-160, Lisbon, Portugal  $\bigcirc$ 

+351 (0) 919 760 832

 $\bowtie$ stephane.couvreur.sueron@gmail.com

scouvreur.github.io github.com/scouvreur linkedin.com/in/stephanecouvreur

# EDUCATION

2013 - 2017Master of Engineering (1st, Hons)

> MECHANICAL ENGINEERING University College London (UCL) Specialization in medical engineering and computing.

2010 - 2013French Baccalaureate (Hons)

Sciences

Lycee Francois 1er Fontainebleau Specialization in mathematics, physics and chemistry (A\*A\*A).

### Awards

Oct 2018 Zaickathon Brand Award

> Award out of 30 teams for creating a team slide interface to Google Slides by scraping HR data from Namely.

Sep 2017 **EPSRC Summer Studentship Prize** 

> Awarded to a summer studentship student for the best research project from a pool of 30 candidates.

Nov 2016 Blonstein Prize

> Awarded to a third year student for the best overall performance in Design.

#### Information

LANGUAGES English, French - fluent

Portuguese, Spanish - conversational

Memberships Data Science Portugal

#### References

Data Science Lead Dr. Ganhao

Feedzai, Lisbon

☑ | fjs.ganhao@gmail.com

Dr. Sauvage Project Supervisor

Great Ormond Street Hospital, London

☑ | e.sauvage@ucl.ac.uk